<resources>
    <string name="app_name">ds-app</string>
    <string name="CSE_des">"
        Located in Hamirpur district of Himachal Pradesh, NIT Hamirpur enjoys a really scenic environment and pleasant weather. Established in the year 1986, as REC Hamirpur, NIT Hamirpur has been declared as the Institute of National Importance under the Act of Parliament, 2007. Established in 1989 as the Department of Computer Science and Engineering, we have an excellent and rich history and an outstanding record of contributions to the profession and community. The Department is well recognized for excellence in facilities and teaching.

        At Present, the Department offers following academic programmes:
        B.Tech. in Computer Science and Engineering (Four Years)
        Dual Degree in Computer Science and Engineering [B.Tech. + M.Tech.] (Five Years)
        M.Tech. in Computer Science and Engineering (Two Years)
        M.Tech. in Mobile Computing (Two Years)
        Ph.D. in Computer Science and Engineering

        The aim of these programmes is to enable students to acquire specialized knowledge for various subjects in computer science and information technology, as well as to enrich the students personal, social and cognitive development to meet challenges of today and tomorrow. The Department is well equipped with high end computers, latest software and state-of-the-art IT infrastructure and all these computing resources are inter-connected with high speed intranet. Our students are exposed to up-to-date curriculum, technology and techniques. The Department has well experienced and dedicated faculty members with different specializations. Our curriculum is modified, enhanced and updated regularly as we introduce new courses to reflect current topics in this fast-changing discipline. Our faculty is involved in cutting-edge research areas, including computer networks, mobile computing, mobile ad hoc networks, wireless sensor networks, security, image processing, data mining, artificial intelligence, computer architecture and reconfigurable computing. The Department prides itself on good career opportunities for students. Our students graduate with more than 100% placement through campus. Many companies of repute show their interest to visit our Institute for campus recruitment."</string>

    <string name="ECE_des">"
        Established in the year 1988, the Electronics &amp; Communication Engineering (E&amp;CE) Department NIT Hamirpur HP, has built an international reputation for excellence in teaching, research and service. Electronics engineers are changing the world to a comfortable global home. The information and technology revolution has been built on the advances of Electronics. The E&amp;CE Department takes pride in its high national rankings and the international recognition its faculty has received from their peers.


        E&amp;CED is making exhilarating progress in areas ranging from microelectronics, mobile communications to VLSI Design Automation. In labs and classrooms, students draw on the expertise and knowledge of our able faculty, integrating practical, hands-on research experience with challenging and interesting course-work.


        The team approach is very warm in the Department of E&amp;CE. A palpable excitement surrounds the Department of E&amp;CE, an enthusiasm pervades every classroom and lab, invigorating our students and spurring on our faculty to fresh innovations. In an age when electronics play a major role in daily life and the promise of nanotechnology is coming to fruition, it truly is a great time to be a part of E&amp;C engineering.


        The pollution free aura of the state surrounded by snow-clad Dauladhar ranges, technological strength and increasing national prominence has presented us with unmatched opportunities for research, education, and service to society. We have grown into a most sought after departments in NIT Hamirpur, adding more faculty and branching into new projects and research areas. Our department maintains close affiliations and has a joint project with CSED. At B.Tech Level, 15th batch of E&amp;CE passed out in 2006. M.Tech. in VLSI Design Automation &amp; Techniques has started from 2006.
   " </string>

    <string name="CHE_Des">
        The Department of Chemical Engineering was established in the year 2013, with a mission to impart high quality engineering education and to mould the students to meet the ever growing demand of technical manpower in the area of Chemical Engineering. The department offers four years B. Tech programme in Chemical Engineering with a total intake of 75 students; M.Tech. program in Chemical Engineering (to be started from July, 2020) with a total intake of 15 students; and Ph.D. program. The department has a strong core curriculum complemented by electives in the important emerging areas of Chemical Engineering. The department comprises of eleven different laboratories for the undergraduates catering to the needs of the curriculum. In addition, analytical instruments, computer facilities and research laboratories for the postgraduates and doctoral resources are already in place. All the faculties are highly qualified and well dedicated to teaching and research in various fields of chemical engineering as well as in different interdisciplinary areas of engineering.


    The Department of Chemical Engineering endeavours towards the fusion of engineering &amp; chemical sciences, biological sciences and advanced materials. Department has well qualified faculty in the core and allied areas of chemical engineering like catalysis and reaction engineering, thermodynamics, transport processes, separations processes, biochemical and bioprocess engineering, microbial biotechnology, electrochemical engineering, fuel cells, synthesis and drug designing, molecular modelling and simulation, computational fluid dynamics, renewable energy, clean and green technology, desalination, industrial effluent treatment, advanced material characterization, supercritical fluid extraction, natural flavours extraction, optimization and modelling and stability, clean coal technology, food processing,
    enhanced oil recovery etc.


    The objective of the department is to bring together the expertise from different domains so as to give international exposure to its students as well as faculty founded on conventional and modern tools. Likewise using modern technological tools, we believe to remain in harmony with nature by utilizing the natural resources, to develop a sustainable process as well as technology on a long term basis. To address the above said goal, interdisciplinary approach towards teaching and research is required wherein faculty from the fields of biotechnology, biological &amp; medical sciences, information technology, nano-technology, engineering, mathematics, environmental sciences and material engineering will work on national and international issues. Hence, our curriculum is designed and structured keeping all these on priority basis which directly allow the students to be in the forefront of rewarding career in the field of CHEMICAL ENGINEERING.


    Within a very short span of time, the department has made an impression of excellence in the field of chemical engineering. The graduated students secured exceptionally good rankings/scores in national and internationally competitive examinations like GATE, GRE, TOFEL, IELTS etc. The graduated students are placed at various reputed organizations through campus interview. Several graduated students have also opted for higher studies at internationally reputed Indian and foreign institutes. In the recent past, the department organized several activities like industry-institute interaction, conference, short-term courses, GIAN, skill-India program etc. and has a plan to organize some more events in near future.


    Apart from improving quality education to the students, the department is also actively involved in research and development activities. Several research projects of total cost more than 1 crore sponsored by external agencies are investigated by the faculty members of the department. The department is pro-active and would like to attract talented students and faculties.


    </string>
    <string name="CE_des">
        National Institute of Technology, Hamirpur was established in the year 1986 and the Civil Engineering Department is part of the institute since its inception. Civil Engineering is considered to be the most versatile branch among all the engineering branches. It is the branch with lot of diversity right from structural to transportation engineering, environmental to hydrology to hydraulics engineering, geology to geo-technology to earthquake engineering; Civil Engineering can be considered as a single largest branch among all the engineering branches. Being one of the primary Engineering Departments of the Institute, the Department of Civil Engineering offers B. Tech., M. Tech. and Ph.D. degrees programmers, accredited by National Board of Accreditation for five years since January 2008 and has been imparting quality education to its students

        Objective

        To provide quality education and training to our graduates to cope up with international standards.
        To conduct regular continuing education and community development programmers.
        To provide extension and consultancy services to Government, private, public and industrial sectors.
        To excel in Industrial Research and consultancy with appropriate national and International linkages and to maintain highest standards in the field of Civil Engineering.
        To be the best-rated departments in India and world in terms of teaching and quality, research contributions, high-end consultancy and academic leadership.
    </string>
    <string name="ME_des">

        The Department of Mechanical Engineering came into its existence right from the inception of the then Regional Engineering College Hamirpur (now National Institute of Technology Hamirpur) in the year 1986 and served as catering department to other disciplines. The discipline of Mechanical Engineering started offering undergraduate programme leading to four year Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech) degree in Mechanical Engineering in the year 1994. The first batch was started with an intake of 30 students which has now been enhanced to 60 students by the Ministry of HRD, Government of India from the session 2006-2007 which has further been enhanced to 90 students. Since its existence, 21 Batches of Undergraduate students with B.Tech Degree in Mechanical Engineering, 14 batches of Postgraduate programme i.e. M.Tech. (Thermal Engineering) and 7 batches of M.Tech. (CAD CAM Engineering) have passed. Apart from this about 20 students have got their PhD in various areas of specialisation i.e. Thermal, Production, Materials and Design. The department has a separate building housing the various laboratories viz : Strength of Materials, Theory of Machines, Dynamics of Machinery, Mechanical Measurements and Control, Heat Transfer, Refrigeration &amp; Air Conditioning, Turbo Machines, Production, CAD/CAM, Metrology &amp; Heat Engines, lecture rooms, seminar room, faculty chambers and office. The major advanced equipments available in these labs are: Computerized two stroke petrol engine test rig, Gas analyzer, Vibration exciter, Dynamometer, Four ball tester (computerized), Sound level meter, Hardness tester (Rockwell &amp; Brinell), Impact tester, Sophisticated metrology equipment, FFT analyzer machine condition monitoring equipment, Journal bearing test rig, Refrigeration tutor, Air conditioning tutor, Ice plant tutor, Various hydraulic turbines (Kaplan, Francis, Pelton wheel) and pumps, Centrifugal blower &amp; Heat transfer equipments, Universal Testing Machine (Computerized), Plasma cutting machine, Pollution checking equipments, Projection manometer, Flaw detector, Computerized vertical machining centre, Robot etc.


        The computer lab of the department is well equipped having PCs of P III and P IV configuration, Printers, scanner facilities and engineering software\'s like - NISA FINITE ELEMENT, FLUENT, FLOW LAB and ANSYS ADVANCED MULTIPHYSICS for the use of students and the faculty as well for academic and research purposes. More software\'s for CAD/CAM are being procured. The department has started a Postgraduate programme leading to M. Tech. Degree with specialization in Computational Methods and Experimental Techniques in Fluid Flow &amp; Heat transfer, admitting students from the session 2005-2006 and offering a Ph.D programme in the areas of Design, Thermal, Production/Industrial. Research scholars have registered and are pursuing their Ph.D work. The department has also submitted proposals to start new PG programmes on CAD/CAM and MBA (Industrial Management). The department has seventeen faculty members fourteen of which hold Ph.D degrees. Rest of our faculty members possess M. Tech. Degrees and are pursuing their Ph.D. degrees. The faculty members are experienced having expertise in Design/Thermal/Industrial/Production and are engaged in research work in the areas of Solar Energy, Heat Transfer, Material Science, Quality and Reliability, Air pollution control, Tribology and Mechanism Design etc apart from teaching. The faculty members have got projects on MODROBS, TAT and R&amp;D from various funding agencies like MHRD, DST, AICTE and TEQIP. A few more projects proposals have recently been submitted for consideration to these agencies. Our graduates are well placed through on-campus and off-campus placement and are holding responsible positions in different organizations viz. ITC, Godrej Consumers, Hero Motocorp., Maruti, Saint Gobain, Future First, Infosys, Wipro, DRDO, ISRO to name a few. Department of Mechanical Engineering is alive to the needs of coming times. Accordingly more facilities and expertise are being developed in the areas of Energy, Materials, Reliability, Robotics, CFD, CAD/CAM etc.

        © 2020 All
    </string>
    <string name="EE_des">
        Electrical Engineering Department, established in the year 1986, is one of the oldest departments of National Institute of Technology Hamirpur. The Department has been imparting quality education at undergraduate and post-graduate level. The faculty members have been active in teaching and research activities. The course curriculum is being revised from time to time so as to keep students abreast with latest developments and emerging technologies. Various departmental laboratories have been strengthened and modernized by procuring state of art equipment’s. The department is also equipped with latest experimental and computational facilities for taking up R&amp;D and consultancy activities in different areas of Electrical Engineering. Alumni of the department are well placed in various reputed government / non-government administrative, academic, research, engineering organizations in the country. Many of them are well settled in various reputed organization in abroad. Department produces not only knowledgeable, skilled, trained employable engineers but also a good citizen having concern with society, environment and ethical issues.
    </string>

</resources>
